Guide to the William Hazlitt Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William Hazlitt collection
1790-1835
GEN MSS 33
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.2
(1 box)
Letters from William Hazlitt to various parties, along with letters by Hazlitt's father (William Hazlitt) and Hazlitt's son (William Hazlitt) as well as three manuscripts by Hazlitt.
Hazlitt, William, 1778-1830
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ongoing collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Type of accession (gift or purchase) and date of acquisition is noted in the box-and-folder list. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of single manuscripts and small groups of manuscripts and other papers, by or pertaining to William Hazlitt, which the library has chosen to group and list as an artificial collection. Materials incorporated into the collection prior to June 1997 have been organized into two series: I. Correspondence and II. Writings.
Authors, English -- 19th century; Hazlitt, William, 1737-1820; Hazlitt, William, 1778-1830; Hazlitt, William, 1811-1893
- Correspondence, Series I
  - HAZLITT, WILLIAM [1737-1820]
    - 2 ALS to his son, William Hazlitt, 1790 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Gift, 1954.
  - HAZLITT, WILLIAM [1778-1830]
    - AL to his father, William Hazlitt, 1790 [Jul 24?] (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 2 ALS to Taylor and Hessey, publishers, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 17 ALS to Francis Jeffrey [1773-1850], 1815-1822 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Transcripts of 17 ALS to Francis Jeffrey [1773-1850], 1815-1822 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - HAZLITT, WILLIAM [1811-1893]
    - ALS to J. Macrone, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      This letter discusses Bulwer-Lytton and his contribution to The Literary Remains of William Hazlitt (1836)
- Writings, Series II
  - HAZLITT, WILLIAM [1778-1830]
    - "The Pictures at Hampton Court", n. d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Autograph manuscript
    - Review of "Table Talk Volume II", n. d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Written in an unidentified hand by an unidentified reviewer
    - "The Spirit of the Age", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Autograph manuscript; one leaf only; numbered 8
      Unidentified source.